Guide to the Doris Ulmann Photograph Collection ca. 1910-1934 PR 72
New-York Historical Society
- older, felt hat, mustache, light colored work shirt, suspenders, seated, holding a can in his hand (Item 2975)
  this mat was previously number 2848 (a duplicate number) and was changed to 2975
- two dancers in black gowns, two in light colored gowns [Martha Graham Dancers] (Item 2976)
  this image was numbered 1736 (a duplicate number), was changed to 2976
- seated, leaning on window ledge (?), holding papers, piercing, straightforward gaze [Johnson, James Weldon poet, diplomat, songwriter, and anthologist of black culture] (Item 2977)
  #416-419, 1277, 1512, 1513, 1533-1536, 2031, 2069, 2216, 2236, 2237, 2238-2241, 2271, 2977, same subject, mat and mount missing; note that this image was numbered 2237 (a duplicate number) and was changed to 2977
- older, bald with white/grey hair at sides of head, white/grey beard and short mustache, white workshirt, seated holding cap (?) in lap, right hand resting on cane (Item 2978)
  This is a photogravure print, appears to be cut out of the book, note that it is signed by DU
- older, balding, white hair, round eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated, looking at some papers, left arm resting on desk, small figurines (?) on desk [Smyth, Clifford, Editor International Book Review] (Item 2979)
  Mat and mount missing; three glue marks on back of print; subject is identified in pencil on back of print, not DU's hand
- thick dark hair, curly, suit, tie, vest [Nathan, George Jean, editor, The American Mercury] (Item 2980)
  #1202, 2980 same subject; this print is a photo gravure
- slick medium light hair, parted almost in the middle, bow, tie [Davis, Robert H., Editor, Munsey's] (Item 2981)
  # 1581, 1991, 1992, 2981 are same subject; this is a photo gravure print and appears to be a proof because the DU copyright is not printed in the lower left corner
- middle aged, thinning medium dark hair, parted on side, pinc-nez eyelgasses, jacket, sort of plaid jacket, seated, hands clasped in lap [Croly, Herbert, Editor The New Republic] (Item 2982)
  This is a photo gravure print
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket, seated hands folded [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2983)
  #1990, 2135-2142, 2746-2751, 2937, 2983 same subject; this is a photo gravure print and appears to cut from the book
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie, seated at desk, writing [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2984)
  #1229-1231, 2143-2152, 2724, 2984 same subject
- young middle aged, short straight medium dark hair, parted in middle, rugged-lookin face, pinstripe jacket, tie, seated with left hand on desk, eyeglasses resting on desk [Menken, H.L., Editor, The American Mercury] (Item 2985)
  this is a photo gravure print, appears to be cut from the book, has DU copyright printed in lower left corner
- middle aged, white hair, parted in middle, mustache, round or oval eyeglasses [McClure, Samuel Sidney, Editor, McClure's] (Item 2986)
  #2217, 2927, 2986 same subject
- middle aged, curly somewhat thick white hair, bushy eyebrows, suit, vest, tie, seated at desk, holding a lighted cigarette in left hand, ashtray and pad of paper on desk [Hoffman, Arthur Sullivant, Editor, Adventure] (Item 2987)
  This is a photo gravure print, appears to be cut from book because it has DU copyright printed in lower left corner
- older middle aged, thinning curly white hair, pince nez eyeglasses, trim mustache, suit, vest, polka dot tie, holding a book [Cross, Wilbur, Editor, The Yale Review] (Item 2988)
  This is a photo gravure print and appears to be a proof; has several details circled in pencil with notes (not DU's hand) like "take down", "soften hightlights", etc.
- curly, light colored hair, smiling, pin striped suit, tie, vest, seated at desk, hands, sissors, papers resting on desk [Crowell, Merle, Editor, The American Magazine] (Item 2989)
  This is a photo gravure print and appears to be cut from book as is has the DU copyright printed in lower left corner
- light or white straight hair, middle aged, mustache, double breasted suit, tie, seated, hands crossed over leg [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2990)
  #1577-1580, 2214, 2990 same subject; this is a photo gravure print, DU copyright printed in lower left corner
- medium gray jacket, vest, patterned tie, dark graying hair, dark eyebrows, seated with papers in hands [Sell, Henry Blackman, editor, Harper's Bazaar] (Item 2991)
  s#1108, 1141-1148, 2991 same subject; this is a photo gravure print, DU copyright printed in lower left corner
- middle aged, curly medium dark hair, seated with open book, daffodils [Cutting, Elizabeth Brown, editor, North American Review] (Item 2992)
  #2935, 2992 same subject; this is a photogravure
- middle aged, very dark short straight hair, parted in middle, mustache, jacket, tie [Sedgwick, Ellery, Editor, Atlantic Monthly] (Item 2993)
  #2928, 2993 same subject
- middle aged, thinning straight medium dark hair, parted on side, round eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated leaning with elbows on a desk, holding a pencil in his right hand [Townsend, Reginald T., Editor, Country Life] (Item 2994)
  This is a photo gravure print, DU copyright in lower left corner
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes, suit, vest, striped tie, seated with right arm over back of a chair [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2995)
  #2175-2190, 2759, 2995 same subject
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, seated, holding cigarette in right hand, ring on pinky finger [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2996)
  #2114-2124, 2996 same subject; this print is a photo gravure, DU copyright in lower left corner
- round, dark rimmed eyeglasses, dark hair, suit, vest, striped bow tie, seated, holding a lighted cigarette in right hand [Harriman, Karl Edwin, Editor, The Red Book Magazine] (Item 2997)
  #1584-1590, 2997 same subject; this is a photo gravure printe, DU copyright in lower left corner
- middle aged, thinning medium dark hair, pince nez eyeglasses, striped suit, vest, tie, seated left hand in trouser pocket, right hand holding a lighted cigarette [Canby, William Seidel, Editor, The Saturday Review of Literature] (Item 2998)
  #974, 1113, 2998 same subject
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache, seated [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2999)
  1073, 1286-1288, 2125-2134, 2999 same subject
- older middle aged, white wiry bushy hair, monocle, suit, vest, seated with small open book or note [Herford, Oliver, editor, Life] (Item 3000)
  #2932, 3000 same subject; this is a photo gravure print, DU copyright in lower left corner
- young, jacket, vest, tie, short, thick, straight salt and pepper hair, seated, looking intently into camera, smiling, suit, vest, tie [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century] (Item 3001)
  #2222, 2666-2672, 2681-2683, 2720, 3001 same subject
- middle aged, bald, round eyeglasses, seated in DU's studio chair, suit, vest, tie, book in lap [Strauss, Samuel, Editor, The Villager] (Item 3002)
  #2655, 3002 same subject; this is a photo gravure print, DU copyright on lower left corner
- round dark rimmed eyeglasses, thick medium light hair with pencil [Farrar, John (Chipman), editor, The Bookman] (Item 3003)
  #1582, 3003 same subject; this is a photogravure print, DU copyright in lower left corner
- gray suit, vest, tie, smooth medium light thinning hair, seated with book or notes on desk or table, oval eyeglasses [Cosgrave, John O'Hara, Editor, the Sunday World] (Item 3004)
  #1571-1576, 2760, 3004 same subject; this is a photo gravure print, DU copyright in lower left corner
- woman, short, light colored, curly hair, middle aged, light colred scarf draped around neck, dark dress, short strand of pearls around neck [Chase, Edna Woolman, Editor, Vogue] (Item 3005)
  #613, 755, 2934, 3005 same subject; this is a photogravure print, DU copyright in lower left corner
- middle aged, thinning dark hair, stout, suit, vest, tie, holding papers in hand, seated [Page, Arthur Wilson, editor, World's Work] (Item 3006)
  #1247, 2930, 3006 same subject
- middle aged, stout, short hair, mustache, seated with notes at desk [Vance, Arthur T., Editor, Pictorial Review] (Item 3007)
  #2933, 3007 same subject; this is a photo gravure print; CU copyright in lower left corner
- middle aged, thinning medium light hair, mustache, double breasted jacket, vest, tie, seated, holding book in lap [Maclean, Charles Thomas Agnew, editor, "Popular Magazine"] (Item 3008)
  #1169, 2328, 2654, 3008 same subject; this is a photo gravure print; CU copyright in lower left corner
- middle aged, bald, gray hair, mustache, stout, seated, suit, vest, tie [Butler, Nicholas Murray, President Columbia] (Item 3009)
  #1155, 1270, 1324, 2408, 2409, 3009 same subject; this is a photogravure print
- older, balding, light grey hair, oval eyeglasses, mustache, suit, vest, tie, seated [Phillips, John S., Editor, The American Magazine] (Item 3010)
  this is a photogravure print, DU copyright in lower left corner
- young, medium dark thick short hair, parted on side, round eyeglasses, suit, vest, patterned tie, seated holding a piece of paper [Haggard, Sewell, Editor, Everybody's] (Item 3011)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding eyeglasses [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur] (Item 3012)
  #2762-2768, 3012 same subject
- balding, patterned bow tie, suit, vest, seated at desk reading a book, right elbow resting on desk holding up his head [Whigham, Henry James, editor, Town and Country] (Item 3013)
  #816, 1203, 1228, 3013 same subject
- young, very dark straight short smooth hair, pencil thin mustache, pinstripe suit, vest, polka dot tie, seated, hands on knees [Hadden, Briton, Editor, Time] (Item 3014)
  this is a photo gravure print, DU copyright in lower left corner
- balding, medium dark hair, stout, seated, suit, vest, tie, monocle [Shipman, Louis Evan, Editor, Life] (Item 3015)
  #2097, 2163, 3015 same subject
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook] (Item 3016)
  #2753-2757, 2979 same subject